Stanislaw M. Ulam Papers 1916-1984 Mss.Ms.Coll.54
American Philosophical Society
- Series X. Class notes, 1936-1981, 1.0 Linear feet 2 boxes
  - Seminar, 26 Feb. 1976 (Box Series X-2)
  - Seminar in Biology, 27 Feb. 1976 (Box Series X-2)
  - Seminar, 20 Apr. 1976 (Box Series X-2)
  - Class notes-Distances, 23 Apr. 1976 (Box Series X-2)
  - Seminar, 6 May 1976 (Box Series X-2)
    Outline and partial text of ecture
  - Seminar, 13 May 1976 (Box Series X-2)
  - Class notes-Speculations about the Mechanisms of Visual Recognition, 29 Aug. 1981 (Box Series X-2)
    Outlines for talk in T-10
  - Class notes-Applied Mathematics for Physiologists, n.d (Box Series X-2)
    Course outline
  - Class notes-Exam in 272, n.d. (Box Series X-2)
  - Class notebook, n.d. (Box Series X-2)
  - Class notebook, n.d. (Box Series X-2)
  - Class notebook, n.d. (Box Series X-2)
  - Class notebook, n.d. (Box Series X-2)
  - Class notes (unbound) (Box Series X-2)
- Series XI. Student notes and papers, ca.1938-1976, 0.5 Linear feet 1 box
  Notebooks and papers generated by students in Ulam's university classes. Files are arranged alphabetically by student's name. Most students of this series appear to have attended Ulam's classes in mathematics at the University of Wisconsin.
  - Paper "The Notion of Equivalence for Sequences of Sets and of Functions", 19 Jan. 1942; Calvin, Burton H. (Box Series XI-1)
  - Lecture notes for Topological Groups Seminar, 1942; Calvin, Burton H. (Box Series XI-1)
  - Paper "The Calculus of Variations in the Large", 31 Jan. 1941; Calvin, Burton H. and Edwin L. Crowe (Box Series XI-1)
  - Paper "Borel and Analytic Sets", Erickson, Wilhelm S. (Box Series XI-1)
  - Paper "The Jordan Theorem and its Generalization," Math 218, Topology, Gardner, Robert (Box Series XI-1)
  - Paper "Some Properties of Convex Metric Spaces," Math 224, Jan. 1942; Kelly, Paul J. (Box Series XI-1)
  - Paper "E-Transforamtions and a New Coefficient", Lormer, A. P. (Box Series XI-1)
  - Paper "The Property of Baire," Math 218, 31 Jan. 1941; Oberbeck, T. (Box Series XI-1)
  - Paper "Fixed Point Theorems", n.d.; Paige, L. J. (Box Series XI-1)
  - Lecture notes for Math 42, (Probability) #1-7, 193[8?]; R[owen?], Walter B. (Box Series XI-1)
    Photocopy
  - Paper "Linkages, Knots, and Queues" for Topology, Math 218, 1 Feb. 1941; Shaw, Robert Harrison (Box Series XI-1)
  - Lecture notes from M762, Set Theory, 1957; Strait, Peggy (Box Series XI-1)
    From MIT
  - "Bocher's Algebra", n.d.; Unknown (Box Series XI-1)
    Exercises
  - Lecture notes for Math 4, Mechanics Course, n.d.; Unknown (Box Series XI-1)
    From Harvard?
  - Lecture notes for Math 290, 1951; Unknown (Box Series XI-1)
  - Paper "Borel Sets", n.d.; Unknown (Box Series XI-1)
  - "Ulam's Lecture", 5 Feb. 1976; Unknown (Box Series XI-1)
  - Paper "Direct Product Groups," Math 224, 23 Jan. 1942; Wagner, R. D. (Box Series XI-1)
- Series XII. Miscellaneous, memorabilia, and newspapers, 1916-1983, 1.0 Linear feet 2 boxes
  A variety of materials collected by Ulam which pertain to a wide range of his lifelong interests. This very diverse series is arranged alphabetically by folder heading and contains such personal memorabilia as Ulam's collection of business and calling cards, his Polish passport, and his petition for naturalization in the U.S. Many files reflect the major concerns of Ulam's career, including those relating to LASL, the atomic bomb, the H-bomb controversy (between Teller and Oppenheimer), and his visiting lectures. Newspapers documenting important events in Ulam's life are included in this series. The file (labeled "newspapers") is arranged chronologically and contains substantial contemporary information of interest to Ulam. Other newspapers are housed in other "memorabilia" files, which Ulam arranged by topic during his lifetime. For example, the August 6, 1945 issue of the Santa Fe New Mexican reporting the dropping of the atomic bomb on Hiroshima is filed with miscellaneous memorabilia dating 1945-1948.
  Life at Los Alamos during and after World War II is documented by Series XII. Community newsletters, family tour guide booklets, an early map of Project "Y," and war ration booklets used on the site are some of the interesting materials from the series which reflect everyday life at Los Alamos. The earliest item from the entire Ulam collection is found within this series; a 1916 street scene of Ulam's hometown, Lwów, Poland, has been preserved within his collection of postcards.
  - Adventures o f a Mathematician, [1976?] (Box Series XII-1)
    Humorous review
  - Air Force, Secretary of. Invitation to dinner, n.d. (Box Series XII-1)
  - Atomic Test Effects in the Nevada Test Site Region, Jan. 1955 (Box Series XII-1)
    AEC booklet
  - Atomic Tests in Nevada, March 1957 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Automobile permit, 1952 (Box Series XII-1)
    French
  - Business and calling cards #1-5 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Caricature drawing, 1978 (Box Series XII-1)
    SMU
  - Certificates, 1957-1971 (Box Series XII-1)
    Learned societies and scientific events
  - Conference on New Directions in Physics and Chemistry. Los 40th Anniversary, 14-15 Apr. 1983 (Box Series XII-1)
    Photo, banquet speech
    Weisskopf, Victor F.
    See also oversize
  - Einstein, Albert, n.d. (Box Series XII-1)
    Bio. and photo
    See Series XII: Fermi, Enrico
  - Engravings, n.d. (Box Series XII-1)
    Copernicus
    Descartes
    Galileo
    Kronecker
    La Place
    Newton (2)
  - Fermi, Enrico, n.d. (Box Series XII-1)
    Einstein, Albert
  - First Los Alamos Workshop on Mathematics in the Natural Sciences, 12-18 June 1974 (Box Series XII-1)
    Program booklet
  - Gulliver's Travels, extract from, n.d. (Box Series XII-1)
    "loyalty determination"
  - Handbook of Rules and Regulations for Salaried Employees, 1 July 1946 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Hebrew memorabilia, n.d. (Box Series XII-1)
  - Johnson-Humphrey Campaign, 1964 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Kirtland Air Force Base, New Mexico, 1968 (Box Series XII-1)
    Welcome guide
  - Lecture announcements #1, 1949-1974 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Lecture announcements #2, 1976-1983; n.d. (Box Series XII-1)
  - Letters in Mathematical Physics, [1975?] (Box Series XII-1)
    Poster calling for papers and subscriptions
  - Los Alamos Astronomical Society, n.d. (Box Series XII-1)
    By-laws
  - Los Alamos Chess Club Bulletin, 25 June 1953 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Los Alamos Family Days, 16-17 July 1960 (Box Series XII-1)
    Tour guide
    Booklet
  - Los Alamos Family Days, 17-18 July 1965 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Los Alamos Newsletter, no. 17, 13 Feb. 1946 (Box Series XII-1)
  - Los Alamos Community News, Vol. 2, no. 12, 16 June 1960 (Box Series XII-1)
  - LASL News, Vol. 3, no. 11, 1 June 1961 (Box Series XII-1)
  - LASL News, Vol. 4, no. 20, 30 Aug. 1962 (Box Series XII-1)
  - LASL News, Vol. 4, no. 27, 6 Dec. 1962 (Box Series XII-1)
    J.F. Kennedy's visit
  - LASL News, Vol. 4, no. 28, 13 Dec. 1962 (Box Series XII-1)
  - LASL News, Vol. 5, no. 1, 1 Jan. 1963 (Box Series XII-1)
    1st 20 yrs. At LASL
  - LASL News, Vol. 5, no. 14, 28 June 1963 (Box Series XII-1)
  - LASL of the University of CA, 1954 (Box Series XII-1)
  - MIT. The Faculty and Officers of Administration, 1957 (Box Series XII-2)
    Directory
  - MIT. New Members of the Faculty, 21 Nov. 1956 (Box Series XII-2)
  - Mathematical Physics, Doctoral Program. University of Colorado, 1969 (Box Series XII-2)
    Description of dept. with SMU
  - Medicare, n.d. (Box Series XII-2)
    Humorous story
  - Membership and identification cards, 193[?]-1981;n.d. (Box Series XII-2)
  - Miscellaneous memorabilia, 1945-1958; n.d. (Box Series XII-2)
    LASL, atomic bomb, postwar
  - Miscellaneous memorabilia, 1954-1976; n.d. (Box Series XII-2)
    H-bomb controversy
  - Miscellaneous memorabilia, n.d. (Box Series XII-2)
  - Miscellaneous publicity, 1956-1981; n.d. (Box Series XII-2)
    Newspaper, magazine clips
  - Moon, map of, 1963 (Box Series XII-2)
  - Newspaper clippings, miscellaneous, 1943-1982; n.d. (Box Series XII-2)
  - Newspapers, 1945-1979 (Box Series XII-2)
    See oversize Series XII:
    - The New York Times, 7 Aug. 1945 (Box Series XII-2)
      Atomic bomb
    - New York World-Telegram, 7 Aug. 1945 (Box Series XII-2)
    - New York Journal American, 8 Aug. 1945 (Box Series XII-2)
      Russia declares war on Japan
    - The New York Times, 8 Aug. 1945 (Box Series XII-2)
    - Los Alamos Times, 12 Apr. 1946 (Box Series XII-2)
    - Los Alamos Times, 19 Apr. 1946 (Box Series XII-2)
    - Los Alamos Times, 11 Oct. 1946 (Box Series XII-2)
    - The New Mexican, 6 Jan. 1955 (Box Series XII-2)
      Fermi, Enrico
    - Les Échos, 27-31 July 1959 (Box Series XII-2)
      In French, LASL
    - The New York Times, 30 Oct. 1960 (Box Series XII-2)
      Presidential campaign
    - The New York Times, 15 Aug. 1963 (Box Series XII-2)
      Edward Teller and test ban treaty
    - The New Mexican, 18 Dec. 1963 (Box Series XII-2)
      Project ROVER
    - Siracusa Nova, 2 [?] 1964 (Box Series XII-2)
      In Italian
    - Albuquerque Journal, 7 June 1969 (Box Series XII-2)
      Univ. of New Mexico honorary degree
    - The New York Times, 17 July 1969 (Box Series XII-2)
      Moon landing
    - The New York Times, 21 July 1969 (Box Series XII-2)
    - The Daily Telegraph, 25 Aug. 1969 (Box Series XII-2)
    - Rochester Democrat & Chronicle, 19 July 1970 (Box Series XII-2)
      Trinity
    - International Herald Tribune, 1 June 1976 (Box Series XII-2)
      Nuclear reactors
    - Colorado Daily, 18 Sept. 1979 (Box Series XII-2)
      H-bomb
  - Nuclear propulsion publicity, 1958-1962;n.d. (Box Series XII-2)
  - Passport, 1937 (Box Series XII-2)
    Polish
  - Petition for naturalization, Sept. 1942 (Box Series XII-2)
  - Polish American Congress. Heritage Award Dinner, 31 Oct. 1971 (Box Series XII-2)
    Program
  - Polish American Congress. Heritage Award Dinner, 23 Nov. 1975 (Box Series XII-2)
  - Polish memorabilia, 1948-1985;n.d. (Box Series XII-2)
  - Polish newspapers, 1938-1980 (Box Series XII-2)
    - Chwila, 1938 (Box Series XII-2)
    - Nowy Swiat (Polish Morning World), 5 Apr. 1959 (Box Series XII-2)
    - Tygodnik Powszechny, 18 Feb. 1973 (Box Series XII-2)
    - Wiadomosci, 1976-1980 (Box Series XII-2)
  - Polish travel papers, 1934;1939 (Box Series XII-2)
  - Political stickers, n.d. (Box Series XII-2)
  - Postcards, 1916-1972;n.d. (Box Series XII-2)
  - Postcards #1-2, n.d. (Box Series XII-2)
    Blank
  - Presidential Inauguration. Invitation to, 1961 (Box Series XII-2)
    Kennedy and Johnson
  - Profile drawings, n.d. (Box Series XII-2)
    FAU
  - Project "Y", plot plan for, 15 Aug. 1943 (Box Series XII-2)
    Early LASL map (Ulam home-T175A)
    See oversize Series XII
  - Puzzle, n.d. (Box Series XII-2)
  - Scuola Normale Superiore, Pisa, 1966 (Box Series XII-2)
    booklet
  - Security handbook (Box Series XII-2)
  - Stamps, 1956-1973;n.d. (Box Series XII-2)
  - Tourist passes, 1950-1952; n.d. (Box Series XII-2)
  - Ulam, Anna, 1966 (Box Series XII-2)
    Mother's grave
  - United States Air Force Systems Command, 1967 (Box Series XII-2)
  - University Bulletin, Vol. 14, No.35, 9 May 1966 (Box Series XII-2)
    University of California
  - von Neumann, John, 1957 (Box Series XII-2)
    Misc. clippings
  - War ration book, [1945?] (Box Series XII-2)
  - War ration cards, 1945 (Box Series XII-2)
- Series XIII. Photographs and film, 1930-1984, 0.5 Linear feet 1 box, 1 film
  Photographs and negatives, a scrapbook, and three films. The photographs of Ulam, family members, colleagues, places, and events are arranged alphabetically by subject (by last name if the subjects are people) and within each file chronologically. Most of these items are in black and white, and are evenly divided in sizes from 3x5" to 8x10", with a few very small (1x1") or larger (10x12") items. The earliest photograph is of the Lwów Mathematical Conference held in 1930; the latest is of Ulam's 75th birthday party in 1984. A number of scientists are depicted in this series, including Banach, Bethe, Borsuk, Erdös, Fermi, Gamow, Kac, von Karman, and von Neumann. Most of the photographs of Ulam are portraits, some formal, other informal. There is one picture of a very young Ulam (1932) in what appears to be swimming attire. The photographs in the scrapbook are arranged as received, and are in neither chronological nor alphabetical order. The dates covered range from a 1947 photograph of a collage involving a portrait of Ulam created for George Gamow (photographed by Jim Lilienthal) to a number of photographs from 1964 which depict the Dahlgren lecture, the Weizmann dinner, and a Parade Magazine article. The scrapbook includes several interesting images, including an aerial shot of Los Alamos, "The Lodge" at Los Alamos, Laura [Fermi?], von Karman and Bradbury, and Claire and Françoise Ulam.
  There are three 16mm motion picture films, the first of which is titled "Measure and set theory," with a running time of fifty minutes. In this lecture, filmed in conjunction with the Mathematical Association of America in 1966, Ulam outlines the basic principles of measure and set theory including additive or aggregate measures. The other films are "32 stars with r=0.4" (4-inch reel, dated May 25, 1967, and an unidentified film (3-inch reel) which may be a continuation of the "32 stars" film. "Measure and set theory" is stored at the end of the collection.
  - Banach, Stefan, 1949-1978 (Box Series XIII-1)
  - Baudouin (King of the Belgians), n.d. (Box Series XIII-1)
    Los Alamos visit
    Bradbury, N[orris] E.
    Conger, Clement E.
    Hertford, Kenner F.
    Wilson, Paul E.
  - Bethe, Hans, 1982 (Box Series XIII-1)
    See also: Ser.XII. Los Alamos. Conference on New Directions in Physics and Industry
  - Biology conference in Colorado, 197? (Box Series XIII-1)
  - Birthday party, S. Ulam's 75th, 1984 (Box Series XIII-1)
    Matted
    Poster, Eliot
    Thon, Dawn
    Thon, [J.] George
    Ulam, Alexander
    Ulam, Stanislaw
    Weiner, Ste[ve]
  - Bomb test, n.d. (Box Series XIII-1)
    time lapse
  - Borsuk, Karol, n.d. (Box Series XIII-1)
    Borsuk's grandchildren
  - Cambridge [University, England], snapshots of (Box Series XIII-1)
  - Center for Nonlinear Studies, 1981 (Box Series XIII-1)
  - Dieudonne, J. A., n.d. (Box Series XIII-1)
  - ENIAC, n.d. (Box Series XIII-1)
  - Erdös, Paul, n.d. (Box Series XIII-1)
  - Fermi, Enrico, n.d. (Box Series XIII-1)
    Films
    See oversize, and end of coll.
  - Gamow, George, n.d. (Box Series XIII-1)
  - Gordon Research Conference, 1978 (Box Series XIII-1)
    Photo i.d. list
  - Hoerlin, [Hermann], 1964 (Box Series XIII-1)
  - Ingarden, Roman, 1960 (Box Series XIII-1)
    Fryling, Jan
  - International Research Conference on the History of Computing, 1976 (Box Series XIII-1)
    See Ser.I: Metropolis, Nicholas #1, letter 22.XI.1976
  - Kac, Mark, 1982; n.d. (Box Series XIII-1)
    Feigenbaum, M.
  - Kennedy (John F.) visit to Los Alamos, 1962 (Box Series XIII-1)
    Bradbury, Norris E.
  - [Lawrence?, E. O.], n.d. (Box Series XIII-1)
  - Los Alamos, n.d. (Box Series XIII-1)
    Aerial views, housing
  - Los Alamos Workshop on Mathematics in the Natural Sciences, Second, 1976 (Box Series XIII-1)
  - Math[ematical] Soc[iety] Movie Lecture, April 1976 (Box Series XIII-1)
  - Menkes, Zygmund. Sketch of S. Ulam, 1938 (Box Series XIII-1)
    Photo of sketch
  - Menkes, Zygmund [Mrs.] (Box Series XIII-1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box Series XIII-1)
    - Folder #1, n.d. (Box Series XIII-1)
      Sized under 5X10
    - Folder #2, n.d. (Box Series XIII-1)
      Sized 5X10 & over
    - Folder #3, n.d. (Box Series XIII-1)
      large, matted
  - Morrison, Philip, 197? (Box Series XIII-1)
  - Negatives, n.d. (Box Series XIII-1)
    S. Ulam portraits
  - [Notes, Photograph of], n.d. (Box Series XIII-1)
  - Polish Mathematics students convention, Lwow, 1930 (Box Series XIII-1)
    Partial photo i.d. list
    Zjazd Kol Matematyczno-Fizycznych
  - Scrapbook (Box Series XIII-1)
    Miscellaneous portraits, etc.
    See oversize
  - Tennis game at Los Alamos, 1958 (Box Series XIII-1)
    (left to right) Tuck, James; Ulam, Stanislaw; Longmire, Conrad; Dodder, Donald
  - Trinity (Alamogordo) atomic bomb test, 16 July 1945 (Box Series XIII-1)
  - Ulam, Claire, 1945-1958; n.d. (Box Series XIII-1)
    [Grusin?], Rebecca
    - Clair Ulam, at Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory open house, 1955., 1.0 Photograph(s); Clair Ulam, daughter of Stanislaw M. Ulam, sitting at control panels during laboratory open house.
    - Stanislaw and Clair Ulam at Los Alamos Scientific Laboratory open house, 1955., 1.0 Photograph(s); Stanislaw M. Ulam pointing to control panel in laboratory, Clair standing with back to photographer.
      General note
      Handwritten note on back of photograph: "Showing the maniac controls to daughter Clair, open house at lab, 1955."
  - Ulam, Françoise, 1942-1964; n.d. (Box Series XIII-1)
    [von Neumann?, Klari]
  - Ulam, Jozef, 1939 (Box Series XIII-1)
    Gdynia goodbye
    Ulam, Adam
    Ulam, Szymon
  - Ulam, Stanislaw (Box Series XIII-1)
    - Folder #1, 1932-1962 (Box Series XIII-1)
      See Ser.II Unknown #1 (1934)
    - Folder #2, 1964-1969 (Box Series XIII-1)
      Portraits
    - Folder #3, 1973-1983 (Box Series XIII-1)
      Rockefeller [Inst.] photo
    - Folder #4, n.d. (Box Series XIII-1)
      - Stanislaw M. Ulam, wearing hat and holding glass., 1.0 Photograph(s); Informal portrait of Ulam, holding glass.
      - Stanislaw M. Ulam sitting outside with book., n. d.; 1.0 Photograph(s); Ulam seated on on park bench, holding book.
    - Folder #5, n.d. (Box Series XIII-1)
    - von Karman, Theodore, 1961 (Box Series XIII-1)
  - von Neumann, John, 1950-1954; n.d. (Box Series XIII-1)
    Some portraits
    [Ulam?, Françoise]
- Series XIV. Audiotape recordings, ca.1955-1982, 0.5 Linear feet 1 box, 21 tapes
  Audiotapes have been removed from the main collection for storage, and have been assigned call no. Rec. 151. Recordings are primarily of lectures and interviews. See the container listing for further information.
  This audio collection is comprised of an eclectic group of audio formats. There are four (4) 7" reel-to-reel tapes, four (4) 5" reel-to-reel tapes, three (3) 4" reel-to-reel tapes, one (1) 3" reel-to-reel tape (lacks box), and six (6) cassettes. In addition, there are three (3) unboxed 3 3/8" diameter reels. This last group is unidentified, but may be computer data stored on magnetic tape. As none of the tapes were played at the time the collection was processed, and as box/reel labels were often incomplete or lacking, no arrangement has been imposed on the tapes at this time. All reel-to-reel tape is 1/4". One 5" reel (designated "e") is stored in a 7" box.
  - "Stanislaw M. Ulam, Univ. of Calif.", n.d.; a; 7" reel-to-reel
    1 side only, 1/2 track, 3 3/4 IPS. 1 mil polyester. Scotch 229
  - [Unlabeled], n.d.; b; 7" reel-to-reel
    1.5 mil polyester. Scotch 175
  - "Aug 1971. Conversation with Rota.", c; 7" reel-to-reel
    1.5 mil acetate. Scotch 111.
  - "10-12-73. Dr. Ulam's talk at Physics Colloquium", October 12, 1973; d; 7" reel-to-reel
    3 3/4 IPS. 1 mil acetate. Scotch 190
  - "7-12-71, S. Ulam", July 12, 1971; e; 5" reel-to-reel
    Stored in 7" box. Reel label reads "Useis[?] meeting, 1-7-71."
  - "Voice of America Interview with Professor Stanley Ulam by Zdzislaw Bau., April 21, 1976; f; 5" reel-to-reel
    11 mins, 25 secs. In Russian or Polish." 1.5 mil acetate. Scotch 111. Reel underfilled
  - "The Way It Is, Part I." Reel label reads "Paris, 8/72, Prof. Ulam.", August 1972; g; 5" reel-to-reel
    Scotch, no product no. "19cm/s" [7 1/2" IPS].
  - "The Way It Is, Part II.", August 1972; h; 5" reel-to-reel
    Continuation of (g.). Same tape type.
  - One reel labeled "Fortran reel IV, computed go to block program [?] variables.", n.d.; i; Three (3) 4" unboxed reel-to-reels
    Other two reels unlabeled. Possibly stored computer data. All three tapes stored together in a poly-bag.
  - Unlabeled., n.d.; j; 3" unboxed reel-to-reel
  - "S. Ulam -- 2 p.m. -- sci section -- Monday[,] Feb. 14, 1955. Baton Rouge, L[a].", February 14, 1955; k; 4" reel-to-reel
    Reel 1 of 3: See below, tapes (l) and (m). 3 3/4" IPS. 1.5 mil polyester [?]. Scotch 111A
  - Con't from (k). "Reel 2.", February 14, 1955; l; 4" reel-to-reel
  - Con't from (l). "Reel 3.", February 14, 1955; m; 4" reel-to-reel
  - "Ulam talk (Grille[?] 2/82) `Physics', February 1982; n; C-60 cassette
    Scotch Highlander brand
  - "S. M. Ulam, 2 Oct. 1976, Talk #1. American Mathematical Heritage Symposium on the History of Applied Mathematics. U of Texas -- Arlington.", October 2, 1976; o; C-90 cassette
    Ampex 370.
  - Box label: "British Science Museum 1976 Evans Interview (Both Sides).", p; C-90[?] cassette
    Tape label reads: "S. Ulam No. 12 Computer Interview." Generic tape.
  - "Gamow lecture series 10-5-82.", October 5, 1982; q; C-90[?] cassette
    Generic tape
  - "Ulam at Bell Labs.", n.d.; r; C-60 cassette
    TDK C-60SD.
  - "[?] Rota 1/3/82", January 3, 1982; s; C-90[?] cassette
    Generic tape.
- Series XV. Miscellaneous reprints, manuscripts, and journals, 1938-1986, 1.5 Linear feet 3 boxes
  Arranged alphabetically by author. Several folders are filed by journal title when the entire issue is of interest or by title of article when the author is unknown. Most of the materials of this series are reprints, photocopies, typescripts, or autograph manuscripts of scientific papers and reviews prepared by Ulam's colleagues. Notes, data, and abstracts of these papers are filed here as well. It should be noted that Ulam's reprints of journal articles are located in this series, not with the manuscripts of his other published works in Series IX. Some journals containing an article of scientific interest to Ulam, usually dealing with nuclear bombs or LASL, have been saved intact. Rather than removing the specific article, these journals remain as a complete issue and are filed under the author's name. In cases where the entire journal issue appears to have been of interest to Ulam, the journal has been filed by title.
  - The Atom, vol. 1, no. II, Nov. 1964 (Box Series XV-1)
  - The Atom, vol. 4, no. 10, Oct. 1967 (Box Series XV-1)
    SMU retires
  - An integer-valued metric for patterns, 1979; Bednarek, A. R. and S. M. Ulam (Box Series XV-1)
  - Relational structures and theoretical computer science, 1979; Bednarek, A. R. (Box Series XV-1)
  - Mathematical classics, 1959; Bellman, Richard, 1920-1984 (Box Series XV-1)
  - Mathematical classics I-analysis, 1959; Bellman, Richard, 1920-1984 (Box Series XV-1)
  - On the limit of solutions of differential-difference equations..., 1959; Bellman, Richard, 1920-1984 (Box Series XV-1)
  - Measures of non-compact manifolds and their equivalence under homeomorphisms, 1981; Berlanga, R. and D. B. A. Epstein (Box Series XV-1)
  - Comments on the history of the H-bomb, Fall 1982; Bethe, Hans A., (Hans Albrecht), 1906-2005 (Box Series XV-1)
    LASL Science, vol. 3, no. 3
  - Brief history of functional iteration at Los Alamos, 1983; Beyer, W. A. and P. R. Stein (Box Series XV-1)
  - Analytical groups, n.d.; Birkhoff, Garrett, 1911-1966 (Box Series XV-1)
    See Series IX "A collection of mathematical problems"
  - Some mathematical aspects of quantum mechanics, n.d.; Birkhoff, George David, 1884-1944 (Box Series XV-1)
    Folder #1, pp. 1-24
    Folder #2, pp. 25-49
    Folder #3, pp. 50-74
    Folder #4, pp. 75-99
    Folder #5, pp. 110-124
    Folder #6, pp. 125-149
    Folder #7, pp. 150-175
  - Passing of a Great Mind: John von Neumann..., Blair, Clay (Box Series XV-1)
    Art. removed from unknown mag.
  - A quantum-theoretical limitation on the speed of digital computers, 1960; Bledsoe, W. W. (Box Series XV-1)